### **MANIKANDAN M**

salem | 9597373109 | mani.eroom@gmail.com

#### Dear Hiring Manager,

I'm applying for Renal dialysis technician position at your company. Based on the posted description, I HAVE 9 YEARS 8 MONTHS OF WORKING EXPERIENCE, I'm confident that I am fully qualified for the position and will be a strong addition to your team. I would appreciate a job interview at your earliest convience.

Name	Manikandan M
Father's Name	Murugan S
Date of birth	03/07/1994
Gender	Male
Marital status	Married
Languages known	English,Tamil,Kannada
Citizenship	Indian
Permanent address	Kangeyampalayam,
	Thiruchengodu(tk),
	Namakkal(dt),
	Pin:637302
	Mob:9597373109
Experience	9 years 6months
Expecting salery	35000 INR

# **Work History**

# 1.Mohan kumara mangalam Medical College and hospital salem (Nov-2021 to current)

- 2.Manipal Hospitals Salem 2 Salem, Tamil Nadu(Oct-2016 to Nov 2021)
- 3. Manipal Hospitals 2 Bengaluru, Karnataka (03/2015 to 09/2016)
- 4.BGS Global Hospitals 

  Bengaluru, Karnataka (05/2013 to 03/2015)

## **Education**

**HSC: Biology 2011** 

Shri Vinayaga Higher Secondary School - Morepalayam, TN

**Diploma: Dialysis Technology 2012** 

Madras Medical College - Chennai, TN

**Bsc: Psychology 2020** 

Alagappa University - Karaikudi, TN

## **Skills**

- ★ Dialysis treatment
- ★ Team leadership
- ★ Records management
- **★** Patient education

- ★ Direct patient care
- **★** Measuring vital signs
- **★** Equipment maintenance
- **★** Patient services
- **★** CRRT
- **★** RO Maintenance
- ★ Performed routine quality control and safety checks on all equipment.
- ★ Cleaned and connected to access sites, including fistulas, grafts, and catheters, by following infection control protocols.
- ★ Safely transported, transferred, and positioned patients on chairs for treatment.
- ★ Followed directions when mixing dialysate and priming dialyzer with saline or heparinized solutions.
- ★ Explained dialysis procedures and hemodialysis machine operation to patients prior to treatment to ease anxieties.
- ★ Safely transported, transferred, and positioned patients on chairs for treatment.
- ★ Provided care for patients based on physical, psychological, educational and safety criteria.
- ★ Educated patients about procedures, answered questions and provided comforting words to control anxiety and enhance procedure results.
- ★ Monitored patients throughout surgical procedures and tests by using devices such as video recorders and EEGs.
- ★ Cleaned and connected to access sites, including fistulas, grafts, and catheters, by following infection control protocols.
- ★ Sterilized, cleaned, and maintained dialysis machine and equipment.
- ★ Started and ended reverse osmosis water systems and completed water quality monitoring tests.

### Reference

1.Dr.Gopalakrishnan
Nephrologist, PROFESSOR AND HEAD OF THE DEPARTMENT.
MADRAS MEDICAL COLLAGE. CHENNAI.
CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

2.Dr.Anil kumar Nephrologists, HOD BGS Global Hospitals. BANGALORE.

3.DR.ASHOK KUMAR, NEPHROLOGIST,HOD, MANIPAL HOSPITALS, SALEM.

4.Dr.Nagarajan Professor,HOD, GMKMCH,SALEM.